# **MAGGIE CHEW**

(403) 354-5615

MAGGIE.CHEW.89@GMAIL.COM

# **SUMMARY**

I am a passionate problem-solver with an insatiable appetite for new challenges, new opportunities, and new ideas. I work tirelessly to find solutions and improvements to the world around me, and love to use my creativity to empower the successes of others. Having previously worked in the not-for-profit and performing arts fields, I am now in transition to a career in technology as a full-stack developer.

## **TECHNICAL & ESSENTIAL SKILLS**

- Programming Languages:
  - o JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS
  - MERN Stack
- Relationship Management
- Team Coordination & Leadership
- Technical Writing:
  - Cases for Support, Donor & Sponsor Proposals/ Communications
  - Websites, promotional materials

- CRM & Information Management
- Public Speaking & Relations
- Prospect Research
- Client Communication
- Sales & Gift Solicitation
- Academic & Publication Writing
- Polyglot:
  - French Fluency, Spanish capability, some Chinese, German, and Finnish

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

#### PROJECT 3

• Underway; location-based app showing content based on position, potentially using Augmented Reality for content/ Machine Learning for content moderation. Firebase, React Native (Expo.)

## PROJECT 2

• Crime and Disorder (<u>link to project</u>). Using React to fetch City of Calgary 3rd-party data to allow users to get customized data on criminal activity in Calgary. Full MERN stack, CRUD. Github repos: <u>Frontend</u>, <u>Backend</u>

### Project 1

• Get Bucked. Console-based game using MongoDB, Express, Node (Javascript) to do time-based activity. Github repo

### **INTERESTS**

TECHNOLOGY, LANGUAGES (CODING AND OTHERWISE), MUSIC, BAKING, GARDENING, LITERATURE, CURRENT EVENTS



# **MAGGIE CHEW**

(403) 354-5615

MAGGIE.CHEW.89@GMAIL.COM

# **EXPERIENCE**

# LEARNER, FULL-STACK DEVELOPMENT INCEPTIONU EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION

2022 - ONGOING CALGARY, AB

- Cohort 9 of the Full-Stack Development Program
- MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node)/ JavaScript
- Product Management, Team Leadership, Project Management
- Essential Skills (Agile Development, Scrum Methodology, Critical/Systems Thinking)

## FUND DEVELOPMENT COORDINATOR

2018 - ONGOING CALGARY, AB

# Mount Royal University Foundation

- Support of the Major Gifts fundraising team, incl. administrative duties & backup
- Writing: Grant, Sponsorship & Donor proposals
- CRM: Internal Process, Data Entry (RENXT, Banner)
- Solicitation & Stewardship of Gifts

### RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT COORDINATOR

2015 -2017 CALGARY, AB

# CALGARY OPERA

- Donor engagement: Stewardship, Solicitation & Cultivation of annual donors.
- Founded the Allegro Young Adult program (after 2 years, 400+ members)
- Public-facing role: written (study guides, articles), speaking (pre-show Chats, tours).
- Tessitura systems: program & CRM management
- Lead generation, prospect research

## **EDUCATION**

# MASTERS IN PERFORMANCE MUSIC (MAJOR: BASSOON PERFORMANCE)

GRADUATED JUNE 2013

### **BOSTON UNIVERSITY**

- Coursework included performance, music history, music theory, languages, ethnic ensembles
- GPA 3.6

# Bachelors in Performance Music (Major: Bassoon performance)

University of Toronto

- Coursework included conducting, languages, ethnic music & literary studies
- GPA 3.53

GRADUATED JUNE 2011